<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.sonatype.com/tmp/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="intro">
  <title>Overview for 5 days' training</title>

  <section id="intro-sect-intro">
    <title>Background</title>

    <para>During the Scrum Gathering Shanghai 2010, xxx introduced CSD
    (Certificated Scrum Development) activities driven by Scrum Alliance, it
    is quite interesting topic, and this is exactly what I am trying to do in
    the company. Though I keep my comments on CSD as certification.</para>

    <para>I have been in software development from 20 years ago, which I play
    basic language on Apple II, I didn't learn any process until coming to the
    company ??</para>

    <para>Scrum is really good framework...</para>

    <para>This book is better called "Exeperience Scrum with real java
    development"</para>

    <para>Therefore I want to create this kind of materials to share with
    everyone and maybe it could be contributed to Scrum China Alliance.</para>

    <para>This book will not tell you the details of each tool, but it will
    give you lead the students to know what it aims for and can be used during
    the training.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Language matters</title>

      <para>Some people think the it doesn't matter which language ...</para>

      <para>Java development is typical different on C/C++ development</para>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Tool matters</title>

      <para>Ant, maven will impact your daily work, svn,clearcase, git will
      impact your daily work as well</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>How to use the book</title>

    <para>This book is used by teachers mainly and as a reference for the
    students, the teachers</para>

    <para>The materials and five days' arrangement should be adapted for your
    target group based on their java competence.</para>

    <para>Teachers act as product owner as well</para>

    <section>
      <title>Prerequisent?</title>

      <para>most of them should have java development competence using
      eclipse, it is ok for one in each team has no experience on this, since
      we need tester in each team</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Environment</title>

    <para>&lt;add a picture here&gt;</para>

    <para>Let's consider a typical 21 students' training, it will be divided
    into 3 teams from day 2.</para>

    <para>every team will have a assistant or teacher and sit around the
    table</para>

    <para>teams will compete with each other on same tasks for more fun. (the
    result could be quite different)</para>

    <para>Review meeting will be done together, others are done seperated
    ??</para>

    <para>The screen will show the quality (hudson/sonar) for every team
    </para>

    <section>
      <title>Hardware</title>

      <para>One server is used to host the hudson, nexus, svn server, sonar,
      proxy server</para>

      <para>Internet access should be provided in order to people to google
      for the sample codes</para>

      <para>One big screen (or projector screen) is used to show the quality
      result </para>

      <para>Whiteboard is used for planning and daily scrum standup
      meeting</para>

      <para>Every student should bring own notebook (do we want to pair
      programming??) </para>

      <para>Several reference books (Java Power Tools) should be provided for
      reference</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Software </title>

      <para>Eclipse with m2eclipse, ... maven, are packaged in advance</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Quick look 5 days' arrangement</title>

    <para>&lt;add a picture here &gt;</para>

    <para></para>

    <section id="intro-sect-open-features">
      <title>Day 1, Introduction and establish the agile environment</title>

      <para>After the quick review of scrum (students should have scrum
      training already), the related java tools (continuous integration,
      version control system) will be introduced, and every student will
      install them by himself to experience it, though they will use
      pre-installed system for project development.</para>

      <para>It aims to give deep understand how those tools work.</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>09:00-10:00</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Quick introduction of Scrum and environment
            introduction</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>10:00-12:00</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>version control svn, eclipse setup, maven</para>

            <para>break around 10:30 </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>12:00-13:00</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>lunch time, know more from each other and get feedback
            during relax time.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>13:00-15:00</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>install hudson CI </para>

            <para>15 mintues break in end of this session</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>15:00-17:00</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>install nexus server and some 3pp</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>17:00-17:30</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Quick review, summary, and the project introduction</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Day 2: Start first iteration and keep quality in mind</title>

      <para></para>

      <para>.</para>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Day 3: End of first iteration and gain the feedback</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Day 4: Start second iteration and learn TDD with
      refactory</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Day 5: End of second iteration and review the training</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
